OLIVIA HYLAND

Junior Front End Web Developer

+3530876540814

10liviahyland@gmail.com

www.oliviahyland.com

github.com/ohyland

in linkedin.com/olivia-hyland

Personal Profile

I am currently completing a traineeship in Front End Web Development and for nearly over 2 years now I am studying web development. I enjoy the full process of designing and developing websites. Right now I am looking for 12 weeks of work placement as a junior Front End Web Developer with an exciting company.

Technical Skills

- XHTML, HTML5
- CSS3
- JavaScript
- jQuery
- Angular
- GitHub
- Responsive Web Design (RWD)
- Wordpress
- Figma

Soft Skills

- Team-work
- Attention to detail
- Communication
- Time management

Training & Education

Front End Web Developer Traineeship - Finglas Training Centre, Dublin, Ireland

Oct 2019 to Present

QQI level 6 Award

Modules: Web Authoring, Web Development, Interactive Scripting, Work Experience, Project Management

Topics & Technologies covered: XHTML, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Angular, GitHub, Responsive Web Design (RWD), Wireframes, Wordpress (CMS), Figma

Art BA Hons - IADT, Dublin, Ireland

2015 - 2018

Second Class Honours

Projects:

Final year work was exhibited at The Sculpture in Context Exhibition at the Botanic Gardens in 2018. created using Photoshop and Final Cut Pro X.

Work Experience

Code Camp - Dublin, Ireland - Teaching assistant Oct 2019

Duties:

- Assisted the head teacher in delivering lessons
- Provided one on one help to individual students
- Provided guidance to any students falling behind

Laurels B&B - Kilkenny, Ireland - Front of house Oct 2016 - Sept 2019

Duties:

- Ensure the highest standard of customer service
- Responsible for daily administration work i.e. replying to guest emails, answering phones, taking bookings, online marketing.
- Responsible for setting rates to ensure optimal capacity and profit against competition

Cath Kidston - Dublin, Ireland - Sales Assistant Oct - Dec 2019

BJR Services - Kilkenny, Ireland - Household Staff 2015 - 2018